C. Carlo Fazioli

625 H St NE Apt 708 Washington D.C. +1(626)298-1212 □ carlo@carlofazioli.com carlofazioli.com in carlofazioli carlofazioli

I am a research scientist and software engineering generalist with experience in cloud computing and artificial intelligence. I am a lifelong learner confident in my ability to rapidly cultivate new knowledge, as well as drill down into concept details.

Current Position

2018 – Present **Software Engineer**, *Group W, Inc.*, Vienna VA.

Main contributor on a multi-year, multi-million dollar DARPA contract to develop an AI wargaming application. Project responsibilities include:

- Architecting microservices with Kubernetes/Docker on an 11-node 1,240 CPU cluster
- Designing Al algorithms with NNs, MCTS, and RL
- o Developing application source code with python, bash, Django, GNU Make
- Constructing application API to support front end Vue devs
- Managing GitLab issues, branches, merges, releases, and testing and deployment pipelines
- Administrating MongoDB at the mongo shell and with pymongo

General corporate responsibilities include:

- Reviewing academic research literature
- Managing interns

- Contributing to contract proposal BD
- Briefing industry stakeholders

Education

2005 – 2009 Ph.D. Mathematics, University of Illinois at Chicago, Chicago IL.

2000 – 2004 B.S. Mathematics, University of San Francisco, San Francisco CA.

Previous Positions

2016 - 2018 Econometric Modeler, International Monetary Fund, Washington DC.

Collaborated with IMF economists on economic model development; researched, designed, and implemented algorithms for use by IMF staff; pursued exploratory research into technology solutions for IMF institutional needs; addressed technical needs of individual IMF staff.

2013 – 2016 Assistant Teaching Professor, Dept. of Mathematics, Drexel University, Philadelphia,

Developed course and lab materials; lectured, graded exams, monitored students' use of online resources, assigned final grades; assisted students as needed outside of class or in office hours; directed teaching assistants.

2011 - 2013 Postdoctoral Research Associate, Dept. of Mathematical Sciences, New Jersey Inst. of Tech., Newark, NJ.

> Researched, designed, and coded novel algorithms for use in fluid dynamics simulations; briefed research supervisor; presented findings to collaborators and conference attendees.

Hobbies and Interests

- Apache webserver maintenance on GCP
 Advent of Code and CTFs
- Solving the NYT crossword puzzle daily
 Science fiction lit/TV/movies
- Running, cycling, and yoga

- Bug bountying and cybersecurity